Kastle, Leonard; Papers ua902.021
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Leonard Kastle Papers
1940-1996
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ua902.021
18.52 cubic ft.
The collection contains material pertaining to Leonard Kastle, an American composer, pianist, film writer and director. Kastle also served as a Visiting Professor of Humanities and Fine Arts at the University at Albany in the 1980s.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Leonard Kastle donated his papers beginning in 1998.
Biographical History
Leonard Gregory Kastle, American composer, pianist, film writer and director, was born in New York City on February 11, 1929. Following his high school education in Mount Vernon, NY, Kastle began his musical training at the Julliard School of Music in New York City, 1938-40. From 1940-42, he attended the Mannes Music School, where he studied piano with Frank Sheridan and composition with George Szell. From 1942-52, Kastle held a piano scholarship with Paul Wittgenstein. Kastle studied composition at the Curtis Institute of Music in Philadelphia from 1944-50, earning a B.A. in 1950. While at the Curtis Institute, he held scholarships in composition with Rosario Scalero, Gian-Carlo Menotti, and Samuel Barber, and a scholarship in piano with Isabelle Vengerova. In addition, Kastle attended Columbia University from 1947-50. He was a student of conducting with Carl Bamberger in NYC from 1950-52.
Kastle's early professional career was spent on Broadway where he was music directory for revivals of Menotti's The Medium (1950) and The Telephone (1950) and for Weill's Lady in the Dark (1951). He was assistant musical director and conductor for NBC television's Opera Theater from 1955-1959, directing one of his own operas, The Swing (one act, televised by NBC on June 11, 1954), as well as works of other composers. Other operas both written and directed by Kastle include Deseret (an opera in three acts based on the life of the Mormon prophet Brigham Young, televised by NBC on January 11, 1961 and revived in 1978); The Pariahs, (opera in three acts about whaling commissioned by the Deerfield Foundation; completed in 1966; with excerpts performed in Albany, NY in 1985); The Passion of Mother Ann: A Sacred Festival Play (opera trilogy about the Shakers, excerpts performed: The Calling of Mother Ann in Albany, NY in 1985, and The Journey of Mother Ann in Potsdam, NY in 1987); and his one-act children's opera, Professor Lookalike and the Children (performed in Albany, NY in 1988).
Kastle has a number of musical and orchestral compositions to his credit. Among his orchestral compositions are From a Whitman Reader (for voice and orchestra), 1954; Poontoosuc (for baritone and orchestra, performed at Tanglewood on July 4, 1976), 1974-75; and Piano Concerto (performed by the composer as a soloist in Albany, NY in 1981). Kastle's vocal works include Three Walt Whitman Songs (for chorus), 1956; Acquainted with the Night (five songs based on poems by Robert Frost), 1957; Three Songs from Moby Dick (for chorus, winner of the Baxter Prize for choral composition), 1963; and Mass (for chorus, organ, and piano, televised by PBS on December 25,1977; revised version performed in Albany, NY on May 30, 1978). Kastle has also composed chamber pieces including Piano Sonata, 1950; Violin Sonata, 1955 (revised version performed in Albany, NY on March 17, 1986); and Piano Suite, 1957. In addition to his operatic and musical compositions, Kastle wrote and directed the film, The Honeymoon Killers, which was released by Cinerama in 1970. In 1970, the film was chosen by the Museum of Modern Art for inclusion in its film archives, and in 1971 it received the Black Humor Award in Paris. The Honeymoon Killers was re-released nationally in 1992, when it was also shown at the San Francisco Film Festival, the Festivale Internationale Cinema Giovani in Italy, and the Film Forum in New York City. In 1998, the film was featured at the Midnight Sun Film Festival in Sodankylä, Finland.
Kastle received a number of prizes, grants and awards during his lifetime including first prize in the Leschetitsky Piano Competition (1948), a Baxter Prize for choral composition (1963), an NEA grant (1974), and two Meet-the-Composer grants (1981 and 1985).
From 1978 to 1989 Kastle was a visiting professor of humanities and fine arts at the University at Albany, SUNY where he taught composition. After retiring from the University, Kastle continued to teach classes as an adjunct faculty member. He died in May 2011 at the age of 82.
Chronology of Events
1938-1940 Studied at Juilliard School
1940-1942 Studied at Mannes Music School. Held scholarship in composition with George Szell.
1942-1952 Held piano scholarship with Paul Wittgenstein.
1944-1950 Attended Curtis Institute of Music (received B.A. in 1950). Held scholarships in piano with Isabelle Vengerova and in composition with Rosario Scalero, Gian-Carlo Menotti and Samuel Barber.
1947-1950 Attended Columbia University.
1948 Received first prize in Leschetitsky Piano Competition
1950 Music Director of Broadway revival of Menotti's The Medium and The Telephone.
1950-1952 Studied conducting with Carl Bamberger.
1954 From a Whitman Reader for voice and orchestra premiered by the Oklahoma Symphony.
1955 Violin Sonata premiered at the Festival of Two Worlds in Spoleto, Italy.
1955-1959 Assistant Musical Director and Conductor for the NBC Television Opera Theater.
1956 Premiere of opera The Swing on NBC's Opera Theater with Kastle as director. Three Walt Whitman Songs for chorus performed by Tanglewood Chorus.
1957 Acquainted with the Night, premiered on CBS Television program, "Camera Three."
1959 Received commission from Wallace Scudder Foundation to write opera, Deseret.
1961 Deseret premiered on NBC TV's Opera Theater.
1961-1966 Composed opera The Pariahs under a Deerfield Foundation grant.
1963 Received the Baxter Prize for choral composition, Three Songs from Moby Dick.
1969-1970 Wrote screenplay for and directed production of the film The Honeymoon Killers which was released in 1970 by Cinerama.
1971-1976 Wrote screenplays for Wedding at Cana, Aloha and Change of Heart (all unproduced).
1974-1975 Wrote Pontoosuce for baritone and orchestra which received its world premiere at Tanglewood in 1976.
1977-1978 Mass received world premiere on Public Television.
1978-1979 Visiting Professor of Humanities and Fine Arts, State University of New York at Albany.
1979 Wrote screenplay for The Teddy Bear (unproduced). Premiere of chamber song cycle, The Weeping Pleiades.
1980-1981 Completed The Birdwatchers, a play with music.
1981 Piano Concerto premiered by the Albany Symphony Orchestra with Kastle as soloist.
1985 Premiere of The Calling of Mother Ann in Hancock Shaker Village.
1986 Performances of Shaker Dances for flute, horn, violin, cello, and harpsichord by Capital Chamber Artists in Albany, NY and in Castleton, VT. Romanza H.B., commissioned by Castleton State College, performed at the Fine Arts Center, Castleton State College, VT; and at Page Hall, Albany, NY.
1986-1987 Performance of The Calling of Mother Ann and world premiere of The Journey of Mother Ann.
1988 Premiere of children's opera, Professor Lookalike and the Children in Albany, NY, funded by a NYS Arts Council Arts-in-Education grant.
1991 Wrote screenplay for Shakespeare's Dog (unproduced).
1992 Wrote screenplay for Weatherman (unproduced).
2011 Passed away in May at the age of 82.
1938-1940 Studied at Juilliard School
1940-1942 Studied at Mannes Music School. Held scholarship in composition with George Szell.
1942-1952 Held piano scholarship with Paul Wittgenstein.
1944-1950 Attended Curtis Institute of Music (received B.A. in 1950). Held scholarships in piano with Isabelle Vengerova and in composition with Rosario Scalero, Gian-Carlo Menotti and Samuel Barber.
1947-1950 Attended Columbia University.
1948 Received first prize in Leschetitsky Piano Competition
1950 Music Director of Broadway revival of Menotti's The Medium and The Telephone.
1950-1952 Studied conducting with Carl Bamberger.
1954 From a Whitman Reader for voice and orchestra premiered by the Oklahoma Symphony.
1955 Violin Sonata premiered at the Festival of Two Worlds in Spoleto, Italy.
1955-1959 Assistant Musical Director and Conductor for the NBC Television Opera Theater.
1956 Premiere of opera The Swing on NBC's Opera Theater with Kastle as director. Three Walt Whitman Songs for chorus performed by Tanglewood Chorus.
1957 Acquainted with the Night, premiered on CBS Television program, "Camera Three."
1959 Received commission from Wallace Scudder Foundation to write opera, Deseret.
1961 Deseret premiered on NBC TV's Opera Theater.
1961-1966 Composed opera The Pariahs under a Deerfield Foundation grant.
1963 Received the Baxter Prize for choral composition, Three Songs from Moby Dick.
1969-1970 Wrote screenplay for and directed production of the film The Honeymoon Killers which was released in 1970 by Cinerama.
1971-1976 Wrote screenplays for Wedding at Cana, Aloha and Change of Heart (all unproduced).
1974-1975 Wrote Pontoosuce for baritone and orchestra which received its world premiere at Tanglewood in 1976.
1977-1978 Mass received world premiere on Public Television.
1978-1979 Visiting Professor of Humanities and Fine Arts, State University of New York at Albany.
1979 Wrote screenplay for The Teddy Bear (unproduced). Premiere of chamber song cycle, The Weeping Pleiades.
1980-1981 Completed The Birdwatchers, a play with music.
1981 Piano Concerto premiered by the Albany Symphony Orchestra with Kastle as soloist.
1985 Premiere of The Calling of Mother Ann in Hancock Shaker Village.
1986 Performances of Shaker Dances for flute, horn, violin, cello, and harpsichord by Capital Chamber Artists in Albany, NY and in Castleton, VT. Romanza H.B., commissioned by Castleton State College, performed at the Fine Arts Center, Castleton State College, VT; and at Page Hall, Albany, NY.
1986-1987 Performance of The Calling of Mother Ann and world premiere of The Journey of Mother Ann.
1988 Premiere of children's opera, Professor Lookalike and the Children in Albany, NY, funded by a NYS Arts Council Arts-in-Education grant.
1991 Wrote screenplay for Shakespeare's Dog (unproduced).
1992 Wrote screenplay for Weatherman (unproduced).
2011 Passed away in May at the age of 82.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the creation of a selection of Leonard Kastle's works, including orchestral and vocal compositions, operas and screenplays, written between 1954 and 1991. The collection is composed primarily of scores from these musical works, including both hand-written drafts and more finalized versions produced and corrected during the printing process.
Scores of Kastle's orchestral compositions may be found in the series From a Whitman Reader (1954) and Piano Concerto (1981). The piano reduction from Kastle's vocal composition is located in the series Acquainted with the Night (1957). Kastle's operas scores may be found in the series Deseret (1959-61), The Pariahs (1961-66) and The Passion of Mother Ann (1983-87). Kastle's screenplays, both produced and unproduced, may be found in Series 5. They include The Honeymoon Killers (1969-70), Wedding at Cana (1971-76), Change of Heart (1971-75), Shakespeare's Dog (1991) and Teddy Bear (Undated).
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Early Works, 1940-1953, Undated
Series 2 - Vocal Compositions, 1947-1984, Undated
Series 3 - Instrumental Compositions, 1964-1991, Undated
Series 4 - Opera, 1950-1988, Undated
Series 5 - Screenplays, 1975, 1991, Undated
Series 6 - Biographical Material, 1944-1996, Undated
Music; Motion pictures--Production and direction.; Composition (Music); Musicals; Upstate New York (N.Y.); Composition (artistic arrangement); Screenplays; sheet music; Musical performances; UAlbany Faculty & Alumni Papers; Kastle, Leonard
- Early Works, 1940-1953; Undated; 1; 0.82 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1 contains material pertaining to Kastle's early works in the 1940s. There are many musical compositions for the piano as well as music for a ballet. There are also multiple sonatas, preludes and fugues in this series as well.
  - The Begging Letters script, Undated (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 1)
  - Canons and Fugues, Manuscript Score, Undated (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 2)
  - Children's March for the Piano, Manuscript Score, Undated (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 3)
  - "The City Says.. ." Manuscript Score, Undated (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 4)
  - Concerto, 7# Minor, 1945 (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 5)
  - Concerto for Viola and Orchestra I, II, and III Manuscript Score, 1953 (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 6)
  - Concerto for Viola and Orchestra Finale Manuscript Score, Undated (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 7)
  - Elegy on the Death of Franklin Roosevelt, Manuscript Score, 1945 (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
  - Impromptu for Piano, Manuscript Score, 1945 (Oversized 1, Folder 2)
  - Introduction and Fugue, Manuscript Score, 1947-1948 (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 8)
  - Mon Coeur est Vrai, Manuscript Score, ca. 1941 (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 9)
  - Music for a Ballet, Final Score, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 3)
  - Music for a Ballet, Original Pencil Copy, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
  - Music for a Ballet, Score, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, 1946 (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 10)
  - Parlita for Piano, Undated (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 11)
  - Pastoral for Piano, Manuscript Score, 1945 (Oversized 1, Folder 6)
  - Poem for Violin and Piano, Manuscript Score, 1944 (Oversized 1, Folder 7)
  - Polka Manuscript Score, 1945 (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 12)
  - Prelude and Fugue, Manuscript Score, 1947 (Oversized 1, Folder 8)
  - Preludes and Fugues for Piano Manuscript Score, Undated (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 13)
  - Preludes and Fugues Manuscript Score, Undated (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 14)
  - The Queen's Enemies, Manuscript, Piano and Vocal Scores, 1948 (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 15)
  - Sketches for Songs of Eternal Love, Manuscript Scores, Undated (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 16)
  - Solitude, A Song for Dramatic Sporano, ca. 1942 (Oversized 1, Folder 9)
  - Sonata for Piano, Manuscript Score, 1946 (Oversized 1, Folder 10)
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano, 1949 (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 17)
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano, Manuscript Score, 1949 (Box 1 (1-Early Works), Folder 18)
  - Student Assignments, 1945-1946 (Box 2 (1-Early Works), Folder 1)
  - Suite for Woodlands, Manuscript Score, 1947 (Box 2 (1-Early Works), Folder 2)
  - Ten Variations an Fantasy on a theme from Schubert, Manuscript Score, 1949 (Box 2 (1-Early Works), Folder 3)
  - Two Songs for Soprano, Manuscript Score, 1943; Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 11)
  - Uber Allen Gipfeln, Manuscript Score, 1946 (Oversized 1, Folder 12)
  - Untitled Compositions, Undated (Box 2 (1-Early Works), Folder 4)
  - Untitled Music Composition, 1940 (Box 2 (1-Early Works), Folder 5)
  - Variations on a Schobert Theme, Undated (Box 2 (1-Early Works), Folder 6)
- Vocal Compositions, 1947-1984; Undated; 2; 1.26 cubic ft.
  Arranged chronologically.
  Series 2 contains compositions Kastle wrote based on poems, such as those written by Emily Dickinson, Robert Frost, and A.E. Houseman. This also contains compositions for Mass, which was aired on Public Television in 1978.
  - Songs on Poems, A.E. Houseman The Weeping Pleiades, 1947; 1949 (Oversized 1, Folder 13)
  - Songs on Poems, Robert Frost Stopping By Woods on a Snowy Evening, 1948 (Oversized 1, Folder 14)
  - Songs on Poems, Edna St. Vincent Millay Song Cycle, 1948 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 1)
  - Compositions based on the poems of George Barker and Siegfield Sasson, 1949; Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 2)
  - Songs on Poems, James Joyce All Day I Hear, 1949 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 3)
  - Songs on Poems, Oscar Wilde Requiscat, 1949 (Oversized 1, Folder 15)
  - Payer (Soprano), 1951 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 4)
  - Songs on Poems, A.E. Houseman Loveliest of Trees, 1951 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 5)
  - Songs on Poems, A.E. Houseman Into my Heart, 1951 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 6)
  - Songs on Poem, Emily Dickinson If I Should Cease, 1952 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 7)
  - Songs on Poem, Laurie Lee Song in the Country, 1954 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 8)
  - Songs on Poems, W.B. Yeats The Lake Isle of Innesfree, 1954 (Oversized 1, Folder 16)
  - Songs on Poems, W.B. Yeats To an Isle on the Water, 1955 (Oversized 1, Folder 17)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman:Reconciliation, Voice and Orchestral Score, 1955 (Oversized 1, Folder 18)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman:Look Down Fair Moon, Voice and Orchestral Score, 1955 (Oversized 1, Folder 19)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman I Heard You Solemn - Sweet Pipes of Organ, Voice and Orchestral Score, 1955 (Oversized 1, Folder 20)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman:Goodbye My Fancy, Voice and Orchestral Score, 1956 (Oversized 2, Folder 1)
  - Songs on Poems, Justinus Andreas Christian Kerner Stille Liebe, 1956 (Oversized 2, Folder 2)
  - Gloria in Excelsis Deo, Chorus and Orchestra, 1956 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 9)
  - Songs on Poems, Robert Frost Whispers of Heavenly Death and Three Songs on Poems by Walt Whitman, 1956 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 10)
  - Kyrie Elieson, Chorus and Orchestra, 1956 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 11)
  - Songs on Poems, Robert Frost Acquainted with the Night - 5 Songs on Poems by Robert Frost, 1956; 1957 (Oversized 2, Folder 3)
  - Songs on Poems, Robert Frost A Prayer in Spring, 1957 (Oversized 2, Folder 4)
  - Songs on Poems, Robert Frost Nothing Gold Can Say, 1957 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 12)
  - Songs on Poems, Robert Frost Acquainted with the Night, 1957; Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 13)
  - Songs on Poems, Robert Frost Fire and Ice, 1957 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 14)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman From a Whitman Reader, Reviews, 1959; Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 15)
  - Three Whale Songs from Moby Dick, 1961 (Oversized 2, Folder 5)
  - Three Songs from Moby Dick, Proof and Sheet Music, 1961-1962 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 16)
  - Songs on Poems, Herman Melville Pontoosuce, 1967 (Oversized 2, Folder 6)
  - The Rusty Man, 1976 (Oversized 2, Folder 7)
  - Songs on Poems, Herman Melville Pontoosuce Programs, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 17)
  - Mass, Tissues of Piano-Vocal Score, 1977 (Oversized 2, Folder 8)
  - Mass, 1977 (Oversized 2, Folder 9)
  - Mass, 1977 (Oversized 2, Folder 10)
  - Mass, 1977 (Oversized 2, Folder 11)
  - Mass, for Chorus, Soloists, Organ and Piano, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 18)
  - The First Saying, 1979 (Oversized 2, Folder 12)
  - Jubilate Deo, 1979; 1982 (Oversized 2, Folder 13)
  - Songs on Poems, W.B. Yeats -5 Madrigals from the Countess Cathleen, 1981 (Oversized 2, Folder 14)
  - A Meditation on Mother Ann, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 19)
  - Agnus Dei, Chorus and Orchestra, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 20)
  - Benedictus and Hosanna in Excelsis, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 21)
  - "Wanderer, Wanderer", Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 22)
  - Songs on Poems, A.E. Houseman Far in a Western Brookland, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 23)
  - Songs on Poems, Poetry and Notes, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 24)
  - Songs on Poems Carry Her Over the Water (W. H. Auder), Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 25)
  - Songs on Poems, Emily Dickinson My Life Closed Twice, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 26)
  - Songs on Poems, A.E. Houseman With Rue My Heart is Laden, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 27)
  - Songs on Poems, Herman Melville Pontoosuce, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 28)
  - Songs on Poems, Edna St. Vincent Millay Sorrow, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 29)
  - Songs on Poems, David Morton Midnight, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 30)
  - Songs on Poems, David Morton Waking Song, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 31)
  - Songs on Poems White Lotus, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 32)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman Goodbye My Fancy, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 33)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman From a Whitman Reader, Tissues of Piano Reductions, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 34)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman Reconciliation, Early Notes, Undated (Box 1 (2-Vocal Compositions), Folder 35)
  - Songs on Poems, Edna St. Vincent Millay Hycinth, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 1)
  - Songs on Poems, Edna St. Vincent Millay Mariposa, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 2)
  - Songs on Poems, Edna St. Vincent Millay Lament, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 3)
  - Songs on Poems, David Morton Rain Song, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 4)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman From a Whitman Reader, Masters of Parts, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 5)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman Reconciliation, 3 Songs for Voice and Orchestra, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 6)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman Reconciliation, 3 Songs for Voice and Orchestra, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 7)
  - Songs on Poems, Emily Dickinson Of Course I Prayed, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 8)
  - Fragments of Songs, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 9)
  - Recorders of Ages Hence, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 10)
  - Songs on Poems, W.B. Yeats Lay Your Sleeping Head, My Love, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 11)
  - Songs on Poems, W.B. Yeats A Cradle Song, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 12)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman From a Whitman Reader, Piano Reduction, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 13)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman From a Whitman Reader, Tissues of Orchestral Score, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 14)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman From a Whitman Reader, Piano-Vocal Score, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 15)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman From a Whitman Reader, Orchestral Score, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 16)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman From a Whitman Reader, Orchestral Score, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 17)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman From a Whitman Reader, Vocal and Orchestral Score, Undated (Oversized 4, Folder 1)
  - Songs on Poems, Walt Whitman From a Whitman Reader, Vocal and Orchestral Score, Undated (Oversized 4, Folder 2)
  - 5 Songs for Contralto (Records), Undated (Oversized 11, Folder 1-2)
- Instrumental Compositions, 1964-1992; Undated; 3; 2.74 cubic ft.
  Every subseries except Subseries 3 is arranged chronologically. Subseries 3 is arranged alphabetically.
  Series 3 contains musical scores for many of Kastle's works. The series is broken down into subseries according to the six major instrumental compositions found in this collection. Each subseries usually contains a manuscript score, while some contain a published score. Subseries 3, Concerto No. 1, is the only subseries to contain Musicians' parts and tissues of parts.
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano, 1949-1950; 3.1
    - Manuscript Score, 1949 (Oversized 5, Folder 1)
    - Score, 1949 (Oversized 5, Folder 2)
    - Photocopied Score with notes, 1949 (Oversized 5, Folder 3)
    - Program from American Premier, 1950 (Box 1 (3-Instrumental Compositions), Folder 36)
  - Prelude, Nocturne and Dance for Piano, 1957; 3.2
    - Manuscript Score, 1957 (Box 1 (3-Instrumental Compositions), Folder 37)
    - Published Score, 1957 (Box 1 (3-Instrumental Compositions), Folder 38)
  - Concerto No. 1, 1980; Undated; 3.3
    - Concerto No. 1, Undated (Oversized 9)